如果没有那么重要，我们就没有办法抛弃像维度一样重要的东西
There is no way we can throw away something as important as a dimension without there
是一些后果，并有一些非常重要的后果，但我们倾向于
being some consequences and there are some quite significant consequences, but we tend
不要去想他们。
not to think about them.
如果我看一下平行铁路线的这一场景，它们显然会趋同
If I look at this scene of parallel railway lines, they clearly appear to converge and
我们期待着。看着这个场景，我们知道它们是平行线，而这就是它
we expect that. Looking at this scene we know that they are parallel lines and this comes
从我们对三维世界看起来的日常经验来看，但这有点令人惊讶
from our everyday experience with what a three dimensional world looks like, but it’s kind of surprising
世界上平行的事物在我们看来是趋同的，而我们却没有
that things that are parallel in the world appear to us to be converging and we don’t
任何想法都可以。这对我们来说并不令人惊讶。
give it any thought at all. It is unsurprising to us.
这是另一个例子，抬头看着一堆树，它们似乎在融合
Here is another example, looking up at a bunch of trees and they appear to be converging
即使这些树木彼此平行，也是从树木垂直出现的
even though these trees are all parallel to one another, emerging vertically from the
地面平原。
ground plain.
这是摩天轮的另一个例子，我们知道摩天轮是圆形的。
Here is another example of the ferris wheel and we know that the ferris wheel is round.
现在在这个特定的图像中，因为我倾斜地看着它，它显然出现了
Now in this particular image, because I have looked at it obliquely, it clearly appears
是椭圆形的。
to be elliptical.
那么这里发生了什么？嗯，数学上透视投影将线条映射到线条，
So what’s going on here? Well, mathematically the perspective projection maps lines to lines,
但它不保留角度。这意味着世界上的平行线不一定
but it doesn't preserve angles. That means that parallel lines in the world will not necessarily
在图像中看起来是平行的。有些情况会有，但总的来说，
appear to be parallel in an image. There are cases when there will be, but in general,
投影后平行线不保持平行。
parallel lines do not remain parallel after the projection.
映射感知投影的另一种形状是，它将圆锥曲线映射到圆锥曲线。所以一个圆锥形，
The other shape mapping perceptive projection does, is it maps conics to conics. So a conic,
圆锥截面的缩写是通过切割实心锥体得到的形状
short for conic section is the shape that you get by slicing through a solid cone and
虽然形状可以是圆形，椭圆形，抛物线形或双曲线形。
though shapes can be a circle, an ellipse, a parabola or a hyperbola.